Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/carnellbramejr (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Project Management Long Range Planning Public Engagement

Languages

Spanish (Elementary)

Certifications

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

Carnell Brame, Jr., AICP

Dallas-based Senior Planner at Desire Line LLC Dallas, Texas, United States

Summary

I am a city planner based in Dallas (TX). I have over 8 years of experience in community development, planning, and engagement working within municipal government and have recently transitioned to the private sector as a project manager.

I hope to make Planning more accessible and strive to use my role to create better communities for all. My focus on equity and inclusivity permeates my approach to my work from start to finish. I am also a big-picture thinker that is not fond of forgetting the details that take a project or initiative from good to great.

I have a Master's degree in City and Regional Planning from the Georgia Tech Institute of Technology and a Bachelor's in Science Degree in Urban and Regional Planning from East Carolina University, with a minor in Architectural Technology Design. I also have a background in engineering.

I joined the American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP) in 2019.

Experience

Desire Line LLC
Senior Planner/Project Manager
January 2023 - Present (10 months)

Supports Urban and Regional Planning, Grants Management, and Disaster Recovery Divisions as senior planner and project manager.

Halff Associates Senior Planner/Project Manager July 2021 - January 2023 (1 year 7 months)

Richardson, Texas, United States

Worked collaboratively with an interdisciplinary team of planners, landscape architects, and other professionals on a wide variety of planning efforts with

public and private entities ranging from comprehensive plan preparation; park, recreation, and trails planning; active transportation planning; downtown and corridor planning; special area planning; and urban design efforts.

City of Dallas 4 years 5 months

Area Planning Manager April 2019 - July 2021 (2 years 4 months)

Dallas, Texas, United States

Managed planning efforts and interdepartmental coordination efforts between the Planning and Urban Design Department with the Office of Economic Development and the Housing Department in assigned City service areas (Northeast and Southeast). Facilitated improved partnerships and synergy between these departments in order to better execute projects, effectively engage neighborhoods, and implement adopted City policy and programs. Coordinated and provided oversight on planning initiatives, private development, infrastructure improvement, and housing development projects in assigned service areas.

Senior Planner March 2017 - April 2019 (2 years 2 months) Dallas, Texas, United States

Facilitated and managed targeted planning and community engagement processes in support of City of Dallas strategies; advanced livability, economic vibrancy, sustainability, and equity alongside fellow Planning & Urban Design staff and in collaboration with City Departments and community partners; analyzed demographic, organizational, and physical data using ArcGIS and Microsoft Excel.

Jefferson Parish Government Planner II April 2013 - March 2017 (4 years) Jefferson, LA

Worked in the planning research (long-range planning) division for two years. Primarily studied and drafted zoning and text amendments to the Parish's Unified Development Code (UDC) and Comprehensive Zoning Code. Notable projects included the ongoing overhaul of the Parish's UDC (August 2015) which included reformatting, reorganizing, and streamlining cumbersome code terminology.

Transitioned to current planning division in 2015. Participated in managing requests for zoning, subdivision, special permitted use approval, and site plan review.

Managed Planning Department data for the Parish's Geographic Information System.

Staffmark
Staffing Analyst, THD
September 2012 - April 2013 (8 months)

Cobb County
Community Development Agency Intern
April 2011 - April 2012 (1 year 1 month)
Marietta, GA

I worked along other planners in conducting the planning process for the Vinings (GA) Vision Plan, that will set forth a vision for the incorporated community just outside of Atlanta. I worked directly with data to create an existing conditions report that guided several public meeting including a design workshop, and the eventual plan that went before the Board of Commissioners.

Noble Investment Group Starbucks Barista (Raleigh Marriott City Center) May 2010 - August 2010 (4 months)

At the Starbucks Raleigh Marriott City Center I prepared cold and hot drink orders for customers on a daily basis. As part of the Barista position I ran the cash register, stocked supplies, kept the restaurant clean, and strived to make our coffee shop a inviting third place for our regulars and hotel/convention visitors.

East Carolina University
Campus Living - Resident Advisor
August 2009 - May 2010 (10 months)

In the Resident Advisor (RA) position at ECU I had the opportunity to be primarily as a liaison between the university and its students. While being an integral part to running an efficient campus living department, as an RA I worked to engage residents into campus and academic life. Some of these duties and roles included safety monitor, event planner, mediator, and mentor.

University of Miami Resident Assistant, Campus Living August 2007 - December 2007 (5 months)

Liaison between university and students in the areas of safety, housing, academics, and extra-curriculars. In this RA position, I was required to take shifts running the front desk where I provided information, gave directions, signed out tools, acted as receptionist for administrators, provided other help to visitors, residents, and staff using the building.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master's degree, City/Urban, Community and Regional

Planning · (2010 - 2012)

East Carolina University
Bachelors, Urban and Regional Planning · (2008 - 2010)